Courtney Ring Marketing Technologist

A hybrid professional with experience in roles that lie at the intersection of marketing and technology. Specialize in bridging the gap between the two areas by bringing digital solutions to marketing and creativity to technology.

EXPERIENCE

Cigna Global Content Management | January 2016-Present

Web Developer - Technology Early Career Development Program (TECDP)

- Maintain the company's global websites and various microsites
- Lead developer for Cigna's Digital Experience Standards worked with the digital marketing team and an external agency for the implementation
- Lead developer for the Individual & Family Plans open enrollment worked on the plan finder application, microsites, and scripts for component generation
- Participated in the development of the 2017 Medicare website and strategy sessions for the 2018 Medicare website
- Transitioned our Cigna Hong Kong partners onto Teamsite Content Manager worked on defect correction for the revamped site

User Experience Designer - Stretch Assignment

- Spend 1-2 days per week working with the Digital Design and Architecture Team
- Design updates and additions to the Digital Experience Standards
- Serve as the go-between for various projects involving both the Digital Marketing and Content Management teams. Projects include Medicare, Corporate Responsibility, and Offered Cigna Through Work
- Develop a widget library of Digital Experience Standards components to be used by the digital team

Cigna Oneview | June 2015 - December 2015

User Experience Design Intern

- Worked with the UI Design team to make upgrades for Cigna's Customer Service Application
- Converted outdated data presentation into updated prototypes to evaluate ease of use
- Worked on an intern project to develop a web app for caregivers that helps them with caregiving duties Team took first place against two other intern groups

Cigna Social Media Marketing | June 2014 - August 2014 *Marketing Intern*

- Worked to develop and implement marketing strategies that created positive conversation and increased awareness of Cigna's benefits
- Developed a "Healthy Selfie" campaign and wrote copy for customer engagement
- Created new content for each social channel (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and YouTube)
- Managed social channels during New York's "Summer Streets" event to showcase Cigna's participation in the event

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Class of 2015

- Major in Computer Science and Communication Studies, Minor in Spanish
- Graduated with a 3.3 GPA

Study Abroad, Madrid Spain, Winter Semester 2014

- Studied Spanish Language and Culture at IES Abroad
- Studied Communications at the local university, Universidad de Complutense

CONTACT

ce.ring@comcast.net

courtney-ring.com

in linkedin.com/courtneyring710

248.924.5377

AREAS OF FOCUS



Web Development



UI Design



Web Analytics



Optimization



Digital Content



Social Media Marketing

KEY SKILLS

HTML/CSS Photoshop
Python AxureRP

Javascript Google Analytics
SQL HP Teamsite

Percolate BrightEdge

Git C++

For more information CHECK OUT MY PORTFOLIO AT:

WWW.COURTNEY-RING.COM